JEFF SHOMALI

info@jeffshomali.com | github.com/JeffShomali | linkedin.com/in/JeffShomali | 415 504 1135 | San Francisco, Bay Area

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer | Full Stack Web Developer | Mobile Developer

A Full Stack Developer with 5 years hands on experience in Front-End, Back-End, Web and Mobile Development. A profession in web technologies and specialize in MERN and LAMP stack, mobile development with React. Highly familiar with most recent JavaScript frameworks and libraries. In the final semester of pursuing a Bachelor of Computer Science with interest in startup, web or mobile development role.

- Front End Web Development
- Back End Web Development
- Mobile Development

- Development and Testing of Software APIs
- Relational & Non-relational Databases
- Server, Network & Hosting Administration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Markup: NodeJS, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, PHP

Databases & Webservers: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Nginx, Apache, Heroku, Digital Ocean
Frameworks/Libraries: Meteor, Express, Laravel, Bootstrap, SemanticsUI, Material UI, Native Base

CMS: WordPress, Magento, WooCommerce, Drupal, Gatsby, Jekyll

Other Tools & Technology: NPM, Yarn, Yeoman, Webpack, Git & GitHub, Babel, Composer, RNPM

• Text editors & IDEs: Sublime, Atom, Visual Studio Code, PHPStorm, WebStorm

EXPERIENCE

Tutyo — Full Stack Web Developer	2016 - 2017
Purrivacy — Full Stack Web Developer (intern)	2015 - 2016
Freelance Developer	2012 - Present

RELEVANT PROJECTS

San Francisco Bart Application: iOS application for Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART), built in React Native and Flux router. Visual Studio Code Snippet Generator: Web application to generate snippet code for VSCode. Built in React and NodeJS iOS Cryptocurrency App: iOS Cryptocurrency app to watch all coin's market data and news. Built in React Native.

Please visit my GitHub (github.com/JeffShomali) or my personal website (jeffshomali.com) for my most recent projects.

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science. Trident University - Cypress, CA	2016 - 2018
AA in Computer Science. Diablo Valley College - Honor Student with GPA 3.8, Pleasant Hill, CA	2014 - 2016
Certified Advanced Java Programming, Program Design and Computer Architecture from DVC.	2016
Certified Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity	2016

No work sponsorship required. References available upon request.